# **SEAN PHENEGER SOFTWARF ENGINEER**

Full Stack Software Engineer with an emphasis on Front End Development

sean.pheneger.dev@gmail.com

- seanpheneger.dev/#contact
- **\** 7753435607
- Reno NV
- in sean-pheneger/
- wcolts2000

# Skills

#### **LANGUAGES**

**JavaScript** 

HTML5

CSS3

Python

SQL

#### FRONT END FRAMEWORKS

React

Redux

BootStrap

Material U

GatsbvJS

## **BACK END FRAMEWORKS**

Node

**Express** 

Django

### SERVER SIDE DATA MANAGEMENT

PostgreSQL

SQLite3

MySQL

# **Projects**

## Connect Our Kids React Native Mobile App

React | React Native | Redux | EXPO

Worked on a team with 4 other engineers building version 1 of a React Native application to supplement the web version of the existing service for Social Workers to help locate extended family members of foster children to help prevent them from having to be integrated into the foster system if a willing and able family member can be located. I was responsible for building out the navigation, multiple views modal sequences and implementing user activity tracking to have a record of users behavior and interactions with the application

# Hurry Up Print Website

Dec. 2019 to Current

June 2019 to July 2019

HTML5 | CSS3 | PHP | Materialize CSS | MySQL

An e-commerce print shop website built on the LAMP Stack offering the owner an admin dashboard for inputting new products and viewing customers orders and survey/questionnaire responses in addition to product pricing calculators for square footage based products. This is an exploration into Procedural PHP to become familiar with it. Solely responsible for all aspects from creation to deployment

# Personal Resources, Notes and Blog

Oct. 2019 to Current

React | GatsbyJS | ContentfulCMS | SCSS

This site is built out to explore using Gatsby JS to render static pages while still using react and getting SEO benefits with having the pages pre-rendered and meta data being injected into each page. The blog posts can be added using a GUI interface from Contentful CMS and the resources/notes get generated from Mark Down pages. This site demonstrates how a site can be built for a client that is not knowledgeable in coding but still provide them with a means to update and input their own content via the Contentful GUI interface.

# **Employment**

# Lambda School

Remote

Team Lead

Led a diverse team of 9 Data Scientists, Full Stack Web Engineers and iOS developers in completing their capstone project, contributing to the code base, various DevOps tasks, code reviews, and leading daily and weekly stand ups and 1 on 1s.

## Lambda School

Remote Feb. 2019 to June 2019

Aug. 2019 to Sept. 2019

Project Manager/Teacher Assistant

Led a group of 5-11 students through daily 1 on 1s, stand-ups, and support hours to provide code reviews, supplemental lectures on special topics, and share code improvement techniques and tips. Led code review of students' solo projects that tested retention of each week's concepts and material. Directed students to find their own solutions and effectively debug their own code.

# FTL Industries dba Hurry Up Print

Print Production Manager, Graphic Designer

Reno NV Feb. 2016 to Current

Help customer to make an informed decision on what services they can best use for their needs. Produce graphics for advertising and signage for clients. Oversee and assist in the production and application of signage and graphics on a variety of medias to meet the customers needs.

# Taillight Tattoos Vehicle Graphics

Reno NV Apr. 2014 to Nov. 2016

Graphic designer and print production Help customer to make an informed decision on what services they can best use for their needs. Produce graphics for advertising and signage for clients. Oversee and assist in the production and application of signage and graphics on a variety of medias to meet the customers needs.

#### Print 4mat Reno, NV

Production Manager

Help customer to make an informed decision on what services they can best use for their needs. Produce graphics for advertising and signage for clients. Oversee and assist in the production and application of signage and graphics on a variety of medias to meet the customers needs.

# **Education**

# Lambda School

Oct. 2018 to Current

Lambda School: Lambda School is a 6+ month Computer Science & Software Engineering Academy that provides an immersive hands-on curriculum with a focus on computer science, web and mobile development, UX design, and data science.

## Earl Wooster High School

Aug. 1996 to June 2000

Graduated with Honors from the International Baccalaureate Program with college credits in English and Social Studies